

Enrique Zetina

Systems Engineer

3

+52 1 55 22 86 69 19



www.ezetina.com



linkedin.com/in/ezetina



github.com/ezetina86



jenzetin@gmail.com

About me —

I'm a Big Data Engineer with experience working with cloud platforms and developing software using Java and Python. I'm curious and goal-oriented, very good learning and teaching new technologies and collaborating with team members. I have a Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, an Oracle DBA certification and I'm also certified as Google Cloud Data Engineer.

Skills

PL-SQL 90%

Google Cloud Platform 80%

Big Data 70%

Python 60%

[Goal oriented, excellent technical skill, ability to solve problem quickly, team spirit]

Languages —

English 80%

Spanish Native

Education

2006-2013 Bachelor of Computer Science

Antivirtus and Antispam system implemented in a FPGA.

Certifications

2020 Google Cloud Platform Data Engineer GCP

2014 ORACLE Administration Workshop

Latest Courses

2020	Google Cloud Architect preparation course	Linux Academy.
2019	Google Cloud Data Engineer preparation course	Linux Academy.
2019	Big Data Fundamentals	Linux Academy.
2019	Architecting with Google Cloud Platform Specialization	Coursera.

Experience

2019-CurrentBig Data Support Engineer.

EPAM Systems

UAM Azc.

IPN ESIME.

Google Cloud Platform

Provide support to customers using Cloud Platform products, solutions and APIs, including Big Data and related services.

Identify and document product bugs and feature requests and work with internal support teams as well as customers to implement effective solutions.

I work closely with internal support teams to improve cloud products at a senior level.

Working with Big Data technology (Hadoop, MapReduce, HDFS). Writting code using programming languages as Java and Python. Working with NoSQL databases and big data querying tools like Pig, Hive, Impala.

Developing sotutions by using Big Data tools like Apache Beam (Cloud Dataflow) and Apache Airflow (Cloud Composer).

2018-2019 Oracle Developer

4th Source

ESI(Express Scripts) Working on transformation team, developing PL/SQL code to migrate existing systems to new platforms, in this position, I'm getting lots of experience in Java and tools like Kafka and Attunity.

Developing PL/SQL.

Developing web services using Java EE.

Work with tools like Kafka, Zookeeper, Attunity.

2017-2018 Oracle Senior Developer

AsTec

Banco Azteca, member of the team that developed a project called MER, which identified elements that could cause risk on branches, the purpose was to measure risks to take actions and avoid fines.

Devolping PL/SQL code to webapps.

Desing database model to support MER system.

Code functions, procedures, views, sequences, indexes and data

model to interact with Frontend and Backend.